

Yu Ji **UX** Designer

www.jiyudesign.com jiyu.designfl@gmail.com 15810333640

Skills

Sketch Photoshop Illustrator Premiere After Effect Keynote Slack Muarrly

Proficiency



About Me

Hi, I'm Yu, an UX designer. My major is Information Art & design. I study interaction design for 5 years. And I have been working in this area for 5 years. I design website & Mobile app, and some product. I'm interested in Tangible User Interface. I have good logical thinking and communication skills. I'm willing to take responsibility and I'm good in teamwork. I believe a good design should be natural, simple, friendly, and emotional. Design is not only a job but a lifestyle, that is always try to make our life better.

Working Experience

Shanghai

& Beijing

2014-Present 🧘 IBM Design Studio - Senior UX designer

I Leverage IBM Design Thinking, collaborate with PM, sales and Devs, prioritize needs, drive user stories, figure out the real needs behind consumers' requests, design the wireframe and UI. I also do the prototype to get feedback, work with development team to ensure quality of the product, iterate continuously to deliver delightful user experience.

1 yr 2 mos IBM Verse mail / Mail Onboarding Manager

> Verse is business email service that offers social analytics from the cloud to mobile devices or desktops. I design the cognitive mail that helps users to prioritize daily work. And I am responsible for Mail Onboarding Manager platform design.

1 yr 3 mos IBM Connections Docs - Cloud collaborative document editing

> Docs is a socially enabled productivity tool that enables teams to work collaboratively on word processing, spread sheet and presentation files. I have designed main features for all three editors.

IBM Machine Learning for Z/OS 1 mos

> This solution helps organizations ingest and transform data to create. deploy and manage models. I designed the website for the system.

3 mos IBM Mobile First Platform

> This service provides a complete environment to develop apps designed specifically for mobile users. I design the UX for push system.

IBM Design Camper - Austin, Texas Area Jul.-Oct.14

Austin, USA In IBM Austin Design Studio, I learned and practiced IBM Design Thinking, involved in different phases of project as researcher, UX and UI designer, lived with different designers from different IBM studios all around the

2010-2012 A NOKIA Research Center - Design Intern

Beijing I do the Interaction designer for two years in NRC. Learned how to do a real product for real users with different teams. Launch my first mobile application in app market.

Education

2011-2014 Tsinghua University, Academy of Art & Design

Interaction design | Master Degree

Jul.-Sep.12 **1** University of Washington,

Attend the World Lab Summer Institute project for two month. Collaborating with UW Electrical Engineering students

2007-2011 Tsinghua University, Academy of Art & Design Information & Art design | Bachelor Degree

Hobbies















Cat

Baking

Traveling

Drawing

Movie

Music Decration